So I've got two kinds of Prince
Rupert drops that I made here
and a vessel in which
to demonstrate here.
So first I'm going to show you--
they both cool rather quickly,
but one was cooled in air.
One was cooled in water.
This is the one
that's cooled in air.
And by the way, I used to
give a demo in the Glass Lab
where I would take the
Prince Rupert drop,
put it on a sealed table
that we call the marver,
and hit it with a hammer
as hard as I could.
I was never able to shatter
this head with a hammer.
In fact, I dented the
marver so many times
that I stopped doing that demo.
So I have a different way
of doing it now which is--
I won't do that today,
but usually I'll
have a student come and try
to break the Prince Rupert
drop in their hands.
It's really hard to do.
Most people can't do it.
But the air-cooled
Prince Rupert drop
doesn't have the same
kind of strength.
So watch what happens.
Not much.
Well, let's try down farther.
Maybe there's more stress there.
Nope, not [INAUDIBLE].
Let me try one more time.
Maybe where it's thicker maybe
there will be more stress.
Maybe a little.